why is it so hard to center a div well
it used to be in this video we're going
to take a look at 12 different ways to
center a div
(Music)
so back in the 90s the only way to
center something was by using a table
layout please don't ever do that now
here's the basic setup we have a div
with the classic parent and then another
div inside that with the class of child
and then here's the basic css styles to
make it look cool so for our first real
example we're going to make the parent
container position relative and the
child container positioned absolute
that's going to allow us to set the top
right bottom and left position of the
child so we'll set the top and left
positions to 50
but notice that this puts the top left
corner of the box in the center we can
account for that by using transform to
translate or move the x and y positions
of the box by negative 50 each and now
it's perfectly in the center for the
third example we'll leave the relative
and absolute positions but this time
we'll set all sides top right bottom and
left to zero and then add margin auto
this is going to force our content into
the center or we can just consolidate
all of the positions the top right
bottom and left into one property called
inset and that works the exact same way
for our fifth example we're going to use
display flex on the parent container and
then we'll add justify content which is
going to center our box horizontally and
then align items we'll center our box
vertically with this method there's no
need to style the child container now
alternatively if we have multiple child
containers and we want to specify which
to center we can move those properties
to the child by using the self version
so here we're setting a line cell to
center or don't use any content or item
alignment at all just set margin to auto
on the child we can do something similar
with a grid layout let's set display to
grid and then justify content center and
align items center grid also gives us a
shorthand so we can replace the justify
content and align items with place item
center and again if we want to specify
which child elements get centered we can
move those properties to the child or
use the shorthand of place though or
just set the margin to auto on the child
hopefully that was helpful give this
video a like and subscribe for more
content like this
(Music)
you