in this video you will learn how to
create a skimmer Shimmer how to create a
shimmer like this if you need something
like this which is a little bit more
complex you can click the link in the
description of this video personally I
think it's way too complex they have
over 300 line of code for this simple
example we have a total of 77 line of
code and I will show you how to do this
step by step so let's start from scratch
first thing first we need to create a
shimmer view widget this one will be a
stateless widget and we'll return inside
a column the column will have a cross
AIS alignment. start in order to align
everything on the left after this inside
the children we will use another widget
called the Shimmer box this will also
require a stateless widget but we will
need to create a Constructor we will
create a int flex and a double width the
flex will be used for the height of the
current Shimmer box widget we will
return an expanded Widget the expanded
will have the flex inside
the child will be a fractionally sized
box inside we can put the width factor
that is coming from the Constructor
after this inside the child of the
fractionally sized box you will create
your container the container will have a
padding and then a decoration the
decoration will have a color of black
opacity and a border radius of 15 the
next thing is to add the Shimmer box
inside the Shimmer view so I will add
multiple of them inside the children we
have have three Shimmer box widget and
three sized box widget this will create
one item so if we replicate this
multiple time this is what you will end
up with you can modify the code as much
as you want that's it see you in the
next one bye